SUNMI SHIN

2904 Katonka Ct, Antioch, TN 37013 | (937) 956-1738 | sunmishin9559@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/sunmishin9559 | GitHub: github.com/sunmishin9559 | Website: sunmishin9559.github.io

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Developer with 3+ years of experience in designing, developing, testing, and debugging while staying focused on enhancing efficiency, stability, and scalability of system resources under strict deadlines. Searching for my next developer role to grow and enhance my technical skills and knowledge.

KEY SKILLS

Programming Java EE, C/C++/C#, Python, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5/CSS, Bootstrap, Node.jS, React JS

Databases Oracle SQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Others Microsoft Office, Maven, Spring MVC, AWS, Windows Server 2012R2, Apache, Tomcat, Git, SVN

WORK EXPERIENCE

Hankook Tire America Corporation

Nashville, TN

Web Specialist / Web Developer

2022-07 to PRESENT

- Transferred SVN repository to Git repository to manage source codes with decentralized version and improve work efficiency with other developers.
- Designed and developed a responsive web application utilizing mainly JavaScript and jQuery for front-end, Java and Java MVC Framework for back-end, and OracleDB to manage the plant Entry/Exit.
- Developed a process on a web system for Container Tracking to improve visibility of the container's status and reduce shipping expenses.
- Developed 5+ management pages not only for admin employees to manage the information or files on the web system but also for web systems to avoid hard coding.
- Planned, wrote and debugged web application with complete accuracy.
- Scheduled a meeting with other teams to discuss the improvements and announce the updates on web systems.

Hankook Tire Manufacturing Tennessee, LP.

Clarksville, TN

Production System Specialist / Web Developer

2019-10 to 2022-07

- Maintained Oracle DB for MES to resolve the issue and improve plant production process by understanding procedures written in PL/SQL.
- Maintained the source code on 3 web systems by using Git and SVN.
- Worked on the development and support of the Maven Spring MVC web application.
- Migrated on premise server to Bastion Server with Amazon Web Services (AWS).
- Created user-friendly dashboard and reports on web systems for customers to provide summary of their order status, and information of the products.
- Developed a web application written in C# interfaced with Oracle DB to monitor production status efficiently.
- Developed a responsive website in Java EE, Jquery, JavaScript, HTML and CSS, and created an interface with SAP ERP.
- Used AJAX JSON, and HTTP Methods to transfer data from the front-end(client) written in JavaScript, HTML, and CSS to the back-end(server) written in Java for RESTful API.
- Designed and developed a process on a web system for sending/receiving quotation and purchase order documents with vendors, and reduced the lead time for the process by 20%.
- Analyzed data from Oracle DB and SAP ERP with SQL for the web systems to make the operation automatic and efficient, and increased the usage on the web systems by 15%.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Wright State University

Dayton, OH

Bachelor of Computer Science, magna cum laude

2014-05 to 2018-12

Wright State University

Dayton, OH

Certificate, Cyber Security Analytics

2018-01 to 2018-12